Guide to the Frank Whitson Fetter Papers, 1902-1992
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- General Research, 1923-1981. (Box 36)
  - Alphabetical Files (Box 36)
    - Newspapers: (Box 39)
      - I-XVI, (2 folders) (Box 39)
      - Miscellaneous: (Box 39)
        - 1955-1971, undated (Box 39)
        - Articles before 1932 (Box 39)
    - Note issues of London private banks, 1955-1962, undated (Box 39)
    - Peru, Indiana, undated (Box 39)
    - Politics: Clippings, 1932 (Box 39)
    - Public record office, undated (Box 39)
    - Rice, Thomas Spring, 1970 (Box 39)
    - Scranton emergency currency of 1918, 1931-1948, undated (Box 39)
    - Selegman letters: Notes on library holdings--Kress, Yale, 1954-1970, undated (Box 39)
    - Senior, Nassau William: Correspondence and research, 1958, undated (Box 39)
    - Silver, 1935-1945, undated (Box 39)
    - Smith, Adam, 1956-1988, undated, (7 folders) (Box 39)
    - Studies in the industrial revolution, 1960, undated (Box 39)
    - Taylor currency material, undated (Box 39)
    - Temperature in Ireland, undated (Box 39)
    - Terminology, 1935, undated (Box 39)
    - Thornton family, 1970-1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Thornton, John (Dartmouth), 1963-1968, undated (Box 39)
    - Thornton, Robert, 1790-1814 (Box 39)
    - de Tocqueville: (Box 39)
      - Correspondence, 1948-1991, undated (Box 39)
      - Research, 1955-1991, undated, Tradesman, undated; (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Unemployment, 1964-1965, undated (Box 39)
    - United Irishmen, undated (Box 39)
    - United States of America: Notes on reading, 1961-1970, undated (Box 39)
    - War debt: Clippings, 1933 (Box 39)
    - Wills, 1977 (Box 39)
    - Wilson, James, 1954, undated (Box 39)
    - Wood, Stuart, 1939-1965, undated (Box 39)
    - Wordsworth and defaulted debts, 1938-1948, undated (Box 39)
  - Cards and Film (Box 39)
    - Acts of 1816-1819 (Box 39)
    - Atkinson, Jasper, 1826-1829 (Box 39)
    - Attwood, Thomas, undated (Box 39)
    - Banking and Business cycles, undated (Box 39)
    - Banking: Currency, undated (Box 39)
    - Bank runs, undated (Box 39)
    - Bibliography of British Monetary, 1777-1813, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Bibliography of British Monetary, 1814-1875, (8 folders) (Box 40)
    - Bibliography: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 40)
    - Bimetallism, undated (Box 40)
    - Biographical, 1959, undated (Box 40)
    - British economy, undated (Box 40)
    - British information: 19th Century, 1970-1974, undated, (4 folders) (Box 40)
    - British Monetary: Miscellaneous, 1797-1875, undated (Box 40)
    - Bullion Committee, undated (Box 40)
    - Bullion report, 1810 (Box 41)
    - Capacity to pay, undated (Box 41)
    - Chancellor of Exchequer and other committees, undated (Box 41)
    - Coffee: General, undated (Box 41)
    - Colonial currency, n.d (Box 41)
    - Commercial banking organizations, undated (Box 41)
    - Conversion funds, undated (Box 41)
    - Danish B.O.D., undated (Box 41)
    - Decimal coinage, undated (Box 41)
    - Economic development, undated (Box 41)
    - Edinburgh review, 1951-1952, undated (Box 41)
    - Export of capital, undated (Box 41)
    - Favorable balance: (Box 41)
      - undated, (4 folders) (Box 41)
      - England, undated (Box 41)
      - U.S.A., foreign, undated, (2 folders) (Box 41)
      - Federalist papers, undated, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - Fiat money, undated (Box 41)
    - Financial institutions, undated (Box 41)
    - Foreign exchange, undated (Box 41)
    - Foreign investments, 1949, undated (Box 41)
    - Gold standards, undated (Box 41)
    - Gresham's Law, undated, (5 folders) (Box 41)
    - Gross National Product, undated (Box 41)
    - Hamburgh, undated (Box 41)
    - Historical myths, undated (Box 41)
    - History of Economic Thought, 1958, undated (Box 41)
    - Horner, Francis, 1956-1959, undated (Box 41)
    - Horton, Wilmot, undated (Box 41)
    - Index numbers, undated (Box 41)
    - International Finance EC.402 precept notes, undated (Box 41)
    - >International monopolies, undated (Box 41)
    - International trade: (Box 41)
      - undated (Box 41)
      - Bibliography, undated (Box 41)
    - Kansas County bonds, undated (Box 41)
    - Library holdings, 1959, undated (Box 41)
    - Make-Work argument, undated (Box 41)
    - Mature economy, undated (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, (11 folders) (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, (9 folders) (Box 43)
    - Mitchison, undated (Box 43)
    - Monetary history of United States, undated (Box 43)
    - Monetary standards, undated (Box 43)
    - Money and banking bibliographies, undated (Box 43)
    - Newspapers, undated (Box 43)
    - Origin and history of money, undated (Box 43)
    - Overend, Gurney and Co., undated (Box 43)
    - Pamphleteer, undated (Box 43)
    - Periodicals, undated (Box 43)
    - Place of money in economic life, undated (Box 43)
    - Political and social, 1941-1949, undated (Box 43)
    - Price changes, undated (Box 43)
    - Price stabilization, undated (Box 43)
    - Problem debt, undated (Box 43)
    - Propensity, undated (Box 43)
    - Protection, undated (Box 43)
    - Qualities of good money, undated (Box 43)
    - Quality theory, undated (Box 43)
    - Quality theory, undated, (3 folders) (Box 44)
    - Quotes, undated (Box 44)
    - Rookes, John, undated (Box 44)
    - Russia, undated (Box 44)
    - Sharp, Richard, undated (Box 44)
    - Smith, Adam, undated, (5 folders) (Box 44)
    - Statistics, undated (Box 44)
    - Supply and Demand market price, undated (Box 44)
    - Tariff, undated (Box 44)
    - de Tocqueville, undated (Box 44)
    - Torrens, Robert, undated (Box 44)
    - Tyler, John, undated (Box 44)
    - Valorization, undated (Box 44)
    - Value of money, 1932, undated (Box 44)
    - Wheatley, John, undated (Box 44)
  - Published Articles and Pamphlets (Box 44)
    - Book reviews: (Box 44)
      - Miscellaneous, correspondence, research and notes, 1932-1977, undated, (6 folders) (Box 44)
      - Money and Empire: the International Gold Standard: Manuscript, correspondence, and research, 1976 (Box 44)
      - Our National Debt: Its History and Its Meaning Today, manuscript and correspondence, 1949, undated (Box 44)
      - Robbinson Torrens: Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 44)
    - Revue Economique Internationale, manuscript and correspondence, undated (Box 44)
    - The Economists Tariff Protest of 1930: (Box 44)
      - Article and manuscript, 1940 (Box 44)
      - Articles, notes and miscellaneous, 1923-1932 (Box 44)
      - Clippings, 1923-1928 (Box 44)
      - Clippings, 1928-1936, undated (Box 45)
      - Correspondence, 1930-1942 (Box 45)
    - The Economists' Tariff Protest of 1930: (Box 45)
      - Editorials by Frank W. Fetter, 1930-1934 (Box 45)
      - Notes: Congressional debates, 1930 (Box 45)
      - Tariff research notes, 1930-1932 (Box 45)
    - 1932: Some Neglected Aspects of Gresham's Law (Box 45)
    - 1933: (Box 45)
      - The Chilean Debt Payment of 1891 (Box 45)
      - Congression Tariff Theory (Box 45)
      - Gresham's Law and the Chilean Peso (Box 45)
      - The Myth of Competitive Advantage (Box 45)
      - The New Deal and Tariff Policy (Box 45)
      - The Real Tariff Issue (Box 45)
    - 1935: The Term Favorable Balance of Trade (Box 45)
    - 1936: (Box 45)
      - China and the Flow of Silver (Box 45)
      - U.S. Balance of International Payments (Box 45)
    - 1939: Pryme Library of Economics (Box 45)
    - 1941: Some Neglected Aspects of the Wool Duty (Box 45)
    - 1942: (Box 45)
      - The Bullion Report Reexamined (Box 45)
      - The Life and Writings of John Wheatley, (4 folders) (Box 45)
      - The Role of Governmental Credit in Hemispheric Trade (Box 45)
    - 1947: History of Public Debt in Latin America (Box 45)
    - 1948: (Box 45)
      - A New Look at Inflation (Box 45)
      - The United States and World Trade (Box 45)
    - 1949: Commercial Treaties for Encyclopedia Britanica (Box 45)
    - 1950: Legal Tender During the English and Irish Bank Restrictions (Box 45)
    - 1953: “The Authorship of Economic Articles in the Edinburgh Review ”, (4 folders) (Box 45)
    - 1954: (Box 45)
      - “A Probable Source of Copinger's On the Authorship of the First Hundred Numbers of the Edinburgh Review ” (Box 45)
      - Witch Hunt in the Lincoln Country, (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - 1955: Does America Breed Depressions? (Box 45)
    - 1955: The Editions of the Bullion Report, (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - 1957: (Box 46)
      - Bibliographical Aids to Research (Box 46)
      - European Convertibility (Box 46)
    - 1958: “The Economy Articles in Quarterly Review and Their Authors”, (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - 1959: (Box 46)
      - The Politics of the Bullion Report: Jasper Atkinson, (4 folders) (Box 46)
    - 1960: “The Economic Articles in Blackwood's Edinburgh Magazine and their Authors”, (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - 1961: The Russian Loan of 1855: A Postscript (Box 46)
    - 1962: (Box 46)
      - “Economic Articles in the Westminster Review and Their Authors”, (2 folders) (Box 46)
      - List of publications, undated (Box 46)
      - Robert Torrens: Colonel of Marines and Political Economist, (5 folders) (Box 46)
      - 1962: Robert Torrens: Colonel of Marines and Political Economist, (2 folders) (Box 47)
    - 1965: Economic Controversies in the British Reviews (Box 47)
    - 1967: (Box 47)
      - “A Historical Confusion in Bagehot's Lombard Street ” (Box 47)
      - Some Pitfalls in the Use of Bank of England Statistics, (3 folders) (Box 47)
    - 1968: (Box 47)
      - Articles on T. E. Cliffe Leslie and Thomas Tooke (Box 47)
      - Lenin, Keynes, and Inflation, (3 folders) (Box 47)
    - 1969: The Rise and Decline of Richardian Economics, (2 folders) (Box 47)
    - 1972: Russia Revisited: Impressions After Forty Years (Box 47)
    - 1974: An Early Memory of Joseph Schumpeter (Box 47)
    - 1975: The Influence of Economists in Parliament on British Legislation from Richardo to John Stuart Mill (Box 47)
    - 1980: Who Were the foreign Mercenaries of the Declaration of Independence? (Box 47)
    - 1981: Are Economists of Any Use? (Box 47)
  - Bound volumes (Box 64)
    Materials from Fetter's library, including a small amount of correspondence and a review of Erich Roll's History of Economic Thought.
    - Roll, Erich: History of Economic Thought (Box 64)
    - Fetter's book review, notes, draft, and correspondence re: History of Economic Thought (Box 64)
    - Gray, Alexander: The Development of Economic Doctrine, 1934 (Box 64)
    - Political Economy Club, 1921 (Box 64)
    - Haney, Lewis: History of Economic Thought, 1920 (Box 64)
- Personal Files, 1915-1991. (Box 64)
  Comprised of the following subseries: Alphabetical files, Biographical Material, Financial Papers (1920-1988), Student Papers (>1915-1926) and travel (1920-1988). The Alphabetical files contain autographs, certificates, newsletters, newspaper clippings, printed programs, and political action correspondence. The Biographical Material files include army discharge papers, guest books, a marriage certificate and wedding announcements, medical records, obituaries and resumes. The Financial Papers contain expense books, income tax returns, real estate closing papers and stock certificates. The Student Papers cover course notes, research material, papers, his dissertation, as well as transcripts and grade books. The last sub-series, Travel, includes correspondence, business cards, maps, travel brochures and travel guides, as well as passports and visas.
  Arranged by topic.
  - Alphabetical Files (Box 64)
    - American Association of Retired Persons, undated (Box 47)
    - Autographs of economists, undated (Box 47)
    - Certificates: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 47)
    - Civil liberties, 1937 (Box 47)
    - Canoeing, 1976-1987, undated (Box 47)
    - Dukakis, 1975, undated (Box 47)
    - Economists for McGovern/Shriver, 1972, undated (Box 47)
    - Events: Miscellaneous, 1955-1987 (Box 47)
    - Forestry, 1969-1991 (Box 47)
    - Hanover: (Box 47)
      - Parking, 1975, undated (Box 47)
      - Road issues, 1972-1975, undated (Box 47)
      - Water Company, 1971-1984, undated (Box 47)
    - Haverford College, 1966-1971, undated (Box 48)
    - Hermes typewriter, undated (Box 48)
    - Horse-Shoe Trail Club, Inc., 1990, undated (Box 48)
    - Illinois political campaign, 1956, undated (Box 48)
    - Izaak Walton League of America, 1968-1980, undated (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous, 1918-1972, undated (Box 48)
    - Ozone Club, 1935-1947 (Box 48)
    - Planting, woodland improvement, 1969-1971 (Box 48)
    - Princeton Club, 1972 (Box 48)
    - Railroads, 1947-1974, undated (Box 48)
    - Religious Society of Friends, 1935-1950, undated (Box 48)
    - Russian posters, ca. 1970s (Box 48)
    - Sadsbury monthly meeting, undated (Box 48)
    - Skiing, 1968-1974, undated (Box 48)
    - Stamp collection, undated (Box 48)
    - Strafford Historical Society, 1963-1971, undated (Box 48)
    - Sugaring, 1968-1970, undated (Box 48)
    - Swathmore, 1939-1991, undated (2 files) (Box 48)
    - Tree farm, 1980 (Box 48)
    - United States involvement in Cambodia, 1969-1972, undated, (3 folders) (Box 48)
    - Waldensians: Italy, 1950-1964, undated (Box 48)
    - Washington's Birthday Cross-Country Ski Touring Race, 1969-1970 (Box 48)
    - Watergate, 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Biographical Material (Box 48)
    - Awards, 1982 (Box 48)
    - Business cards, undated (Box 48)
    - Clippings: (Box 48)
      - Personal, 1920-1973, undated (Box 48)
      - Professional, 1934-1967 (Box 48)
    - Death certificates and obituaries, 1991 (Box 48)
    - Genealogy, undated (Box 48)
    - Guest book: Frank and Polly Fetter, 1929-1984, (2 folders) (Box 48)
    - Letters of recommendation, 1920 (Box 48)
    - Marriage to: (Box 48)
      - Elizabeth Pollard, 1929 (Box 48)
      - Elizabeth Stabler, 1978 (Box 48)
    - Medical: Miscellaneous, 1951-1990 (Box 48)
    - Military service, 1918-1957, undated (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous, 1975-1989 (Box 48)
    - Resum?nformation and biographical sketches, 1923-1068, undated (Box 48)
  - Financial Papers (Box 48)
    - Banking information, 1988 (Box 48)
    - Bankshare information, 1949, 1983 (Box 48)
    - Expense books, 1920-1935, (3 folders) (Box 48)
    - Expenses, 1924-1952 (Box 48)
    - Income tax material, 1945 (Box 48)
    - Income tax material, 1924-1953, undated, (14 folders) (Box 49)
    - Karstadt stock, 1940-1969, undated (Box 49)
    - Loan schedule: Payment made by Frank W. Fetter to his father, 1936-1949 (Box 49)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961-1989, undated, (2 folders) (Box 49)
    - Real Estate, Sharon, Vt.: (Box 49)
      - Correspondence, 1959-1974, undated, (2 folders) (Box 49)
      - Deeds, closing papers, surveys, maps, 1955-1965 (Box 49)
      - 5 Canterbury Lane, St. Davids, Pa.: (Box 49)
        - Closing papers, 1939-1948 (Box 49)
        - Correspondence, 1945-1949 (Box 49)
      - 580 Orchard Lane, Winnetka, Ill.: (Box 49)
        - Closing papers, deed, survey, 1948 (Box 49)
        - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1948-1967 (Box 49)
      - Miscellaneous, 1964-1972, undated (Box 49)
    - Retirement benefit information: Correspondence, 1942-1949, undated, (2 folders) (Box 49)
    - Stock certificates, 1921-1926 (Box 49)
    - Stock report: Miscellaneous, 1972-1973 (Box 49)
  - Student Papers (Box 49)
    - Graduate courses: (Box 49)
      - Harvard University: (Box 49)
        - Correspondence, 1931-1933 (Box 49)
        - Corporation Finance (EC 37) notes and reports, 1923-1924 (Box 49)
        - Economic theory notes, 1923-1924 (Box 49)
        - History of the West (Hist. 17a & b) exam, notes, and reports, 1923-1924 (Box 49)
        - United States 1880-1920 (Hist. 39) exam, notes, and reports, 1923-1924 (Box 49)
        - International Finance (Ec 39) notes, 1923-1924 (Box 49)
        - Transportation exams, readings, notes, 1923-1924 (Box 49)
        - Valorization Research (Ec 20): (Box 49)
          - Clippings, articles of interest, 1923-1926 (Box 49)
          - Correspondence, 1931-1933 (Box 49)
          - Federal Congress Debates, 1899-1908, undated, (2 folders) (Box 49)
          - Notes, printed material, undated, (4 folders) (Box 49)
          - Reports, 1924, Jan., undated, (2 folders) (Box 49)
          - Valorization Committee notes, 1908-1910, undated (Box 49)
      - Princeton University: (Box 49)
        - Banking (Ec) notes and reports, 1923 (Box 49)
        - Currency Reform (EC 508) notes and reports, 1924-1925, (2 folders) (Box 49)
        - Economic Doctrines (Ec 504) notes, biography, and report, 1922 (Box 49)
        - Economic Principles (Ec 501) notes, 1921-1922 (Box 49)
        - Government and Business (Ec 407) notes, 1924-1925 (Box 49)
        - History of Money and Banking (Ec 507) notes and report, 1922-1923 (Box 49)
        - Labor Problems (Ec 404) notes and miscellaneous, 1922-1923 (Box 49)
        - Money and Banking (Ec 401) notes, report, 1921-1922 (Box 50)
        - Problems in Transportation (Ec 522) notes, 1922-1923 (Box 50)
        - Public Finance (Ec) notes, 1922 (Box 50)
        - Valorization Research (Ec 20) clippings, 1924, Oct. 19 (Box 50)
        - Valuation and Capitalization (Ec 521) notes, 1922-1923 (Box 50)
    - Harvard University: (Box 50)
      - Financial record, 1923-1924 (Box 50)
      - Miscellaneous: (Box 50)
      - undated (Box 50)
      - Notes/Research for F. J. Turner, 1923-1924, (6 folders) (Box 50)
      - Written work, ca. 1923 (Box 50)
    - Princeton High School: (Box 50)
      - Essay, ca. 1915-1916 (Box 50)
      - Latin I assignments, 1915 (Box 50)
    - Princeton University: (Box 50)
      - Dissertation and notes, 1926, May, undated, (2 folders) (Box 50)
      - Dissertation research notes: (Box 50)
        - Articles of Interest, 1856-1863 (Box 50)
        - Chamber of Deputies reports, 1866-1893, undated (Box 50)
        - Congressional Debates, 1878-1907, undated (Box 50)
    - Princeton University: (Box 50)
      - Dissertation research notes: (Box 50)
        - Government Finance Reports, 1845-1925, undated (Box 50)
        - Minister of Finance Reports, 1866-1920, undated (Box 50)
        - Newspaper articles, 1878-1898 (Box 50)
        - Presidents' messages, 1877-1924 (Box 50)
        - undated (Box 50)
        - Books and Bibliographies, 1897-1921, undated (Box 50)
        - Chamber of Deputies Reports, 1894-1916, undated, (2 folders) (Box 50)
        - Congressional debates, 1908-1915, undated (Box 50)
        - Financial Commission Reports, 1895-1912, undated (Box 50)
        - Newspaper articles, 1910-1925, undated (Box 50)
        - Paper money, undated (Box 50)
        - Printed material, 1885-1932, (3 folders) (Box 50)
      - Miscellaneous Notes: (Box 50)
        - American Coinage, undated (Box 50)
        - Monetary Theory Before 1797, 1932-1959, undated (Box 50)
        - Recent monetary theory, undated (Box 50)
      - Miscellaneous notes and clippings: Economic history, undated (Box 50)
      - Record books, 1921-1923 (Box 50)
      - Student lecture, 1921 (Box 50)
    - Transcripts and grades: (Box 50)
      - Harvard University, 1923-1924, 1942 (Box 50)
      - Swarthmore College, 1916-1920, 1942 (Box 50)
    - Undergraduate courses, Swarthmore College, Political Science 107: Report, 1920 (Box 50)
  - Travel (Box 50)
    - Argentina: (Box 50)
      - Financial papers, 1922 (Box 50)
      - Miscellaneous, 1922 (Box 50)
      - Visa, 1922 (Box 50)
    - Austria: (Box 50)
      - Brochures, 1976 (Box 50)
      - Business cards, undated (Box 50)
      - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 50)
      - Language course certificates, notes, miscellaneous, 1965-1974 (Box 50)
    - Canada: (Box 50)
      - Brochures, clippings, 1978-1982 (Box 50)
      - Itinerary, notes of Betty Fetter, 1980 (Box 51)
      - Miscellaneous, 1985 (Box 51)
    - Czechoslovakia, Hungary: Business cards, undated (Box 51)
    - England: (Box 51)
      - Clippings, 1938-1955, (3 folders) (Box 51)
      - Itinerary, 1981 (Box 51)
      - Miscellaneous, 1937-1938, (2 folders) (Box 51)
      - Program, map, 1971 (Box 51)
      - Visa, driver's license, miscellaneous, 1954-1955 (Box 51)
    - Europe: (Box 51)
      - Brochure, miscellaneous, 1965-1986, (2 folders) (Box 51)
      - Itineraries, 1960-1978 (Box 51)
      - Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 51)
    - France: (Box 51)
      - Brochure, 1976 (Box 51)
    - France, Spain, Italy: Business cards, undated (Box 51)
    - Germany: Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 51)
    - Hungary, Russia: Maps, miscellaneous, 1960-1970 (Box 51)
    - Ireland, England: Business cards, undated (Box 51)
    - Italy: Miscellaneous, 1957-1981, (4 folders) (Box 51)
    - Japan, China: Business cards, undated (Box 51)
    - Maryland: Brochure, 1950s (Box 51)
    - Miscellaneous places, dictionary, brochures, notes, miscellaneous, undated (Box 51)
    - Passports: (Box 51)
      - 1928-1994, (6 folders) (Box 51)
      - Elizabeth P. Fetter, 1926-1987, (2 folders) (Box 51)
    - Portugal: Business cards, undated (Box 51)
    - Russia: (Box 51)
      - Correspondence, 1930, June-Sept. (Box 51)
      - Miscellaneous, 1930 (Box 51)
      - Notes, 1930 (Box 51)
    - Scandinavia: (Box 51)
      - Brochure, miscellaneous, 1955 (Box 51)
      - Business cards, undated (Box 51)
      - Hineranes, miscellaneous, 1956-1964 (Box 51)
    - Scotland: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 51)
    - Sweden: Brochure, 1976 (Box 51)
    - Switzerland: (Box 51)
      - Business cards, undated (Box 51)
      - Correspondence, 1954-1956 (Box 51)
      - Menu, undated (Box 51)
      - Visa, miscellaneous, 1954-1955 (Box 51)
    - United States: (Box 51)
      - Brochures, notes, 1958-1959 (Box 51)
      - Itinerary, 1977 (Box 51)
      - Miscellaneous, 1920, undated (Box 51)
      - United States Embassy: Business cards, undated (Box 51)
- Professional Files, 1925-1990. (Box 51)
  Comprised of the following subseries: Alphabetical Files, Conferences and Seminars (1933-1985), Lectures and Speeches (1928-1981), and Teaching (1925-1990). The Alphabetical Files include material regarding the organizations in which Fetter was actively involved, and contain annual reports, application forms, articles and pamphlets, catalogs, correspondence and memos, editorials, library maps, membership lists, newsletters and newspaper clippings, programs, public hearings and bills, research notes, reports, surveys and telegrams. In the second sub-series, various conferences and seminars that Fetter attended throughout his career are documented with national and international agendas and programs, attendance lists, correspondence, notes and presented papers. The Fellowships and Grants subseries includes copies of his applications, correspondence, news releases, notes and published directories. Fetter was a frequent speaker and the Lectures and Speeches sub-series is comprised of a variety of material documenting these talks. There are articles of interest, lecture notes, outlines and texts of his talks, as well as newspaper clippings and newsletters, and press releases and programs. The final sub-series primarily covers Fetter's teaching experiences before his appointment to Northwestern University, with just a few files during and after the Northwestern years. Typical academic materials are contained here, including course assignments, bibliographies, exams, grade books, readings and syllabi, Fetter's lecture notes, including articles of interest, correspondence and memoranda, newspaper clippings, reports and speeches, as well as his students' papers are contained here. There are also college newspapers and commencement programs. Arranged by topic.
  - Alphabetical Files (Box 51)
    - American Association of University Professors: (Box 51)
      - 1949-1988, n.d (Box 51)
      - Willard Fisher case, 1913-1987 (Box 51)